Ning Gao

(+49) 1522 2441871 Stuttgart, Germany

Doctoral Researcher

ning.gao@de.bosch.com gaobaoding.github.io

I'm a fourth year PhD student at Autonomous Learning Robots (ALR) at KIT supervised by Prof. Gerhard Neumann. I'm also a doctoral researcher at Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence (BCAI), Renningen, Germany. My research interests lie in the field of Meta-Learning and representation learning on Robot Perception & Manipulation.

SKILLS

Languages Python, C++, Bash, SQL, ŁTFX, MarkDown

Tools Git, ROS, Blender

Communication Chinese (native), English, German

WORK EXPERIENCE

Researcher	May 2020 — Present
Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence	Renningen, Germany

Meta-Learning, Representation Learning, Robot Manipulation

Master Thesis StudentMay 2019 — Oct 2019Bosch Center for Artificial IntelligenceRenningen, Germany

Benchmarking deep learning algorithms for 6DoF object pose estimation

Research Intern Oct 2018 — Feb 2019

Bosch Corporate Research Renningen, Germany

Driver's gaze estimation for autonomous driving

Research Intern Mar 2018 — Aug 2018

Bosch Corporate Research Renningen, Germany

Build interior camera system prototype for autonomous driving

Undergraduate Research Assistant Nov 2017 — May 2018

Institute of Measurement and Control Systems (MRT), KIT

Karlsruhe, Germany

Joint tracking for multiple pedestrians and vehicles

Summer Intern Jun. 2015 — Sep. 2015

Daimler Greater China Ltd.

Beijing, China

Engine testing and calibration

EDUCATION

Doctoral Researcher in Computer Science	2020-Present
---	--------------

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karlsruhe, Germany

M.Sc in Mechanical Engineering 2016-2019

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karlsruhe, Germany

B.Sc in Automotive Engineering 2011-2016

Tongji University, Shanghai

Outstanding Graduate Award

Daqing Experimental Highschool 2008-2011

Daqing, Heilongjiang Province

ACTIVITIES

Reviewer of ICRA2021, ICRA2022, IROS2022, CoRL2022, CoRL2023

The Machine Learning Summer School, Tübingen, Germany 2020

PUBLICATIONS

Meta-Learning Regrasping Strategies for Physical-Agnostic Objects

Under review ICRA 2024

CoRL 2023

CVPR 2022

Gao, Ning and Zhang, Jingyu and Chen, Ruijie and Vien, Ngo Anh and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann, Gerhard

SA6D: Self-Adaptive Few-Shot 6D Pose Estimator for Novel and Occluded Objects

Enhancing Interpretable Object Abstraction via Clustering-based Slot Initialization BMVC 2023

Gao, Ning and Hohmann, Bernard and Neumann, Gerhard

What Matters for Meta-Learning Vision Regression Tasks?

Gao, Ning and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Vien, Ngo Anh and Volpp, Michael and Neumann, Gerhard

Category-Agnostic 6D Pose Estimation with Conditional Neural Processes

Gao, Ning and Vien, Ngo Anh and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann, Gerhard

WiCV workshop, CVPR 2022

(+49) 1522 2441871 Stuttgart, Germany

Ning Gao Doctoral Researcher

ning.gao@de.bosch.com gaobaoding.github.io

Li, Yumeng* and **Gao, Ning*** and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann, Gerhard

Signature: Datum: